<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diaries on Hun&#39;s Blog ✍️</title>
    <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diaries on Hun&#39;s Blog ✍️</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Im Hun</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:52:35 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Concerns About the Future</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/%EB%AF%B8%EB%9E%98%EC%97%90-%EB%8C%80%ED%95%9C-%EA%B3%A0%EB%AF%BC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:52:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/%EB%AF%B8%EB%9E%98%EC%97%90-%EB%8C%80%ED%95%9C-%EA%B3%A0%EB%AF%BC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a third-year front-end developer at my current company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe I’ve done many important things here, but when it comes to confidently answering what I’ve accomplished, it feels awkward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, while using the updated ChatGPT 4o, I’ve noticed that I’m increasingly relying on it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always think that there is no such thing as 100% certainty in anything, but as the engine upgrades, it gets closer to providing correct answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I ADHD?</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:52:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/adhd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADHD is a term that I’ve been hearing a lot these days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ADHD(Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s characterized by decreased attention, leading to distractibility and impulsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not considered a mental illness, but rather a developmental disorder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Childhood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back on my childhood, I remember reading 10 or 20 books in one sitting. My mom probably thought she had given birth to a genius.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, after entering elementary school, I stopped reading altogether and spent that time playing games.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trials of 2024</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 12:41:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest trial in my life has come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I made a lot of money from investments, which led to excessive confidence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I kept making big bets, and ultimately, I faced significant losses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a moment when I felt my mental state crumbling every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t focus on work at all, and I experienced panic disorder symptoms for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just then, a project that needed to be completed urgently came up, and for a month, I focused on that work, spending all my time day and night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 목표</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2023goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 13:41:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2023goal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career Growth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first word that comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, the most frightening thing is to be stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These days, I often feel that way, so I plan to revive my blog and write consistently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will revise the existing blog entries I wrote in Notion one by one and migrate them,&#xA;and I will refer to many new topics on Medium to make them my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2022retrospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 13:41:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/2022retrospect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year filled with ups and downs is soon coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2021, when I turned thirty, I only remember living fiercely for a year, betting everything on my goal of transitioning to a developer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And at the beginning of this year, January 2022, I found a suitable job that matched my aptitude.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I came to Seoul carrying a few clothes and a nice coat that my mother bought to congratulate me on getting a job, all packed in a 27-inch suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding a Home with LH Jeonse Loan</title>
      <link>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/lh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 18:22:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://findmytrueself.github.io/en/diary/lh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days, the reality is that in order to earn a salary, one must come to the metropolitan area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you either have to work for a public enterprise, run a business, or do casual or part-time jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, people like me have no choice but to come to the metropolitan area to survive. However, I have no connections here at all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, if I want to live, I need to establish myself in the metropolitan area, but that’s when I have to constantly grapple with housing issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
